原作者名：Scott Manley
视频来源：youtu.be/ph_apgmpYY0
原视频发布日期：20201008
字幕翻译/压制：旋火
Hello it's Scott Manley here.
你好 我是Scott Manley
I love to talk about space hardware and this usually means rockets and spaceships
我喜欢谈论航天设备 这通常是指火箭和飞船
but sometimes there are more mundane everyday items used in spaceflight.
但是更多平凡的日常用品也会用于航天活动当中
In fact one of the most significant things brought to space on John Glenn's first orbital flight
其实在约翰·格伦的第一次入轨飞行中 被带入太空的最重要的东西之一是
was something that he bought in a store.
他在一家商店买的东西
This was the camera which he used to take some of the historic photos of earth.
这是他用来拍摄一些闻名历史的地球照片的相机
As I understand it John Glenn bought the camera on his own
据我所知 约翰·格伦是单独买的相机
because he was concerned that there might be delays in getting something approved for flight
因为他担心在获得飞行许可方面可能会出现延误
if he went through the regular government acquisitions process.
如果他要通过常规的政府采购程序来购买这个设备
I'm not sure why the mission planners hadn't considered a regular camera early in the process.
我不知道为什么任务规划者在计划的初期 没有考虑使用普通相机
Perhaps they'd left it out
也许他们是觉得没必要
because there was a science experiment involving another modified camera on the same flight.
因为在同一次飞行中 有个科学实验使用了另一个改装过的相机
Or it's possible that because the early automated flights in the Mercury program
也有可能是因为早期的水星计划中的自动飞行
had included cameras that took lots of photos of the earth
包含了相机 并拍摄了大量的地球照片
that maybe they couldn't see the advantage in having a human holding a camera and pointing it themselves.
这使得他们看不到人拿着相机拍摄的优势
So yeah John Glenn's camera.
那么 没错 约翰·格伦的相机
It was an Ansco auto set 35 millimeter camera
这是一个Ansco自动设置35毫米相机
which was actually a re-badged version of the first Minolta Hi-Matic.
这实际上是第一台美能达Hi-Matic相机的重新贴牌版本
So this was the first Minolta rangefinder camera with automatic exposure.
那么这是第一台具有自动曝光功能的美能达Rangefinder相机
So it would set both the aperture and the shutter speed using a built-in selenium light meter.
那么它可以通过一个内置的硒测光表来设置光圈和快门速度
And this automation would obviously make it good for use in flight
这种自动化显然使它适合在飞行中使用
when you know John would have his suit on
也就是约翰穿着宇航服的时候
and he'd have limited chance to adjust the controls and possibly also be busy with other things.
这时他不太可能去调整控制 而且还会忙于其他事情
Now to make the camera usable in space NASA engineers took it and they modified it.
那么 为了使相机能在太空中使用 NASA的工程师们对它进行了改造
They flipped the whole camera upside down and they added a pistol grip
他们把整个相机翻转过来 并加了一个手枪握把
with thumb paddles that would actuate the shutter and film winding controls.
这样可以用拇指拨片来驱动快门和胶卷过片控制
These connected physically to the controls on the camera.
这些都与相机上的控制装置相连
Now they also needed a viewfinder so they added that on the top
现在他们还需要一个取景器 所以他们把它加在了相机的顶部
which of course would now be on the bottom.
当然 现在则会在底部
But that would also be helpful because it could be used with the suit helmet closed.
但这也会很有帮助 因为它可以在关上宇航服头盔玻璃罩的情况下使用
The other camera on the flight was a Leica
飞行中使用的另一台相机是徕卡的
which had been modified for a science experiment.
这是为科学实验而改装的
It had been given quartz optics and a prism to perform spectroscopy on stars
在其上安装了石英光学元件和棱镜 以对恒星进行光谱分析
so the experiment would involve taking photos of stars in the constellation of Orion
那么实验就需要拍摄猎户座星座中的恒星照片
and the light from these stars would be dispersed by a prism allowing the spectra to be seen.
而这些恒星发出的光会被棱镜分散 从而使光谱得以显现
But because these images were being taken in space
但由于这些图像是在太空中拍摄的
the spectrum would stretch into the ultraviolet region,
频谱将延伸到紫外线区域
an area of the spectrum which is on the inaccessible to ground-based astronomy.
而这个区域是地基天文学无法获得的
Now I'm sure there's a lot of you out here by the way right now
那么我相信你们中的很多人在这儿会说
who are making comments about how John Glenn wasn't the first space traveler with a camera.
约翰·格伦并不是第一个带相机的太空旅行者
Because of course on Vostok 2 Gherman Titov carried a Soviet Konvas movie camera
因为在东方二号上 没错 是戈尔曼·季托夫 他携带了苏联的Konvas电影摄像机
had about 300 meters of film
还有大概300米长的胶卷
and I hear that during the launch the exposure setting dial broke.
而我听说在发射过程中 曝光设置盘坏了
So Titov pretty much had to guess his way through the exposures
所以季托夫只好猜测他的曝光方式
but he did a pretty good job
但他做得很好
and these are the first images taken by a human in space.
而这些都是人类在太空中拍摄的第一张照片
Gagarin didn't fly with a camera
加加林飞行的时候没带相机
so he could only describe what it looked like over radio.
所以他只能通过无线电描述太空的样子
I'd love to talk more about russian cameras but I don't actually have any sources.
我很想多说一些关于俄罗斯相机的事情 但我实际上没有任何资料来源
So I'm going to focus on the US side of things.
那么我将专注于美国这边
And on the US side of things
而在美国这边
Wally Schirra would be the one to set the future standard for space photography gear.
沃利·施艾拉将成为未来太空摄影设备的标准制定者
When he took a Hasselblad 500C camera on six orbits around the earth in his Mercury capsule sigma seven.
当他带着哈苏500C相机在水星太空舱的西格玛7号上绕地球六圈时
Apparently Wally was a bit of a shutterbug
显然 沃利有点摄影迷
and when he was preparing for his mission
而当他准备执行任务的时候
he asked professional photographers who'd been following the Mercury program, you know, advice.
他咨询了那些一直关注着水星计划的专业摄影师的意见
And based on their advice he bought this Hasselblad camera at a houston photo supply store
根据他们的建议 他在休斯敦的一家摄影用品店买了这台哈苏相机
along with lenses and film magazines.
以及镜头和胶卷盒
So the Hasselblad was a medium format camera.
那么哈苏是一款中画幅相机
It exposed a much larger area four times the area of film
它的曝光面积是电影胶片的四倍
and that meant much higher quality images.
这意味着更高的图像质量
The camera also allowed the changing of lenses
该相机还允许更换镜头
and you could swap out film types between photos
而且你可以在照片之间更换不同类型的胶片
and that would prove to be really useful on later missions.
而这在以后的任务中会被证明是非常有用的
Again the cameras would be modified for flight into space.
同样的 这些相机也会被修改 以便飞向太空
They had a waist level viewfinder and that didn't work in the Mercury capsule
它们有一个腰平取景器 但这在水星太空舱中无法使用
so they took that out and just put a viewfinder on the side.
所以他们就把它拆掉了 只是在相机侧边放了一个取景器
The film cartridges would be modified to hold many more frames of film.
胶卷盒被改装成可以容纳更多的胶片
I think they use hundred frame rolls
我觉得他们用的是百格卷
and they were locked closed so that they couldn't be accidentally opened in space.
而且是锁着的 这样就不会在太空中被意外打开
The surface of course was leatherette.
当然 (原本)表面是皮革的
They stripped that off and then painted everything black.
他们把它剥掉 然后把所有的东西都涂成黑色
The engineers went and looked at
工程师们去看了看
and they figured that they could machine off parts of the casing to reduce the mass.
而他们认为可以通过机械加工的方式来减少质量
So yeah this camera would fly with Wally
那么没错 这台相机最终被沃利带上了天
and then it would also fly with Gordon Cooper on the final Mercury flight.
然后它还会和戈登·库珀一起在水星号的最后一次飞行中使用
And apparently the camera actually ended up in Gordon Cooper's possession
而很显然 这台相机最终还是落入到了戈登·库珀的手中
and it would be later sold at auction for 275 000 dollars.
后来在拍卖会上以27.5万美元卖出
But if you are a camera fan that want a replica
但如果你是一个相机迷 想要一个复制品
there's a guy called Cole Rise who is making Hasselblad replicas for like five thousand dollars.
那么可以去看看Cole Rise 他会做哈苏相机的复制品 差不多要5000美元一台
He has an amazing site where he's pretty much documented the whole process
他的网站很不错 在那里他几乎记录了你想了解的关于这些相机的
and all the stuff you could ever want to know about a lot of these cameras.
整个过程以及各种各样的东西
So anyway most significantly
那么无论如何 最重要的是
this Hasselblad would set the standard for at least the decade to come and further.
这款哈苏相机将至少为未来十年甚至更远的时间里树立标准
Hasselblad cameras became the camera used on GeminI and Apollo.
哈苏相机成为双子座和阿波罗计划中使用的相机
They transitioned from simply taking photos out of windows to actually taking photos while on EVA
他们从简单的从窗外拍照过渡到在舱外活动(EVA)中进行拍照
and yeah they took photo of Ed White on a spacewalk.
是的 他们拍到了爱德华·怀特在太空行走的照片
At that point Hasselblad saw this and they realized that NASA were using their cameras
在那时 哈苏意识到NASA在使用他们的相机
and they got in touch with NASA and began to work directly on cameras for the space program.
之后他们与NASA取得了联系 并开始直接为太空计划研发相机
So for the lunar EVA they developed the 500 EL Data Camera
那么在月球EVA中 他们开发了500EL数据相机
with a silver finish for thermal control.
为了更好的热控制而做成了银色的抛光表面
They had a special low distortion lens
同时配备一个特殊的低失真镜头
and they added the resole plate which is a sheet of glass with the grid of black reference crosses
而他们在那上面加了一块有黑色参考十字的网格玻璃板
which were you know projected onto the image.
这样参考线就被投射到图像上
So these of course were used for extracting measurements from the images off the lunar surface.
那么这些参考线当然是用来从月球表面的图像中提取测量值的
This was an camera designed for science as well as pretty pictures.
这是一台同时为科学和亮丽照片而设计的相机
So Hasselblad's 70 millimeter format would actually continue to be used after Apollo
那么哈苏的70毫米规格实际上在阿波罗之后还在继续使用
through Skylab and well into the Shuttle era.
经过天空实验室 一直到航天飞机时代
But rewinding a bit it was towards the end of the Apollo program
但是 回溯一下 在阿波罗计划的末期
that NASA began to introduce the smaller 35 millimeter Nikon SLR cameras.
NASA开始使用更小的35毫米尼康单反相机
Nikon began working directly with NASA at this time.
尼康在这个时候开始直接与NASA合作
They would make customized versions of their cameras to NASA standards.
他们会按照NASA的标准来制作定制版的相机
And their cameras actually continue to fly in space today.
而他们的相机实际上至今仍在太空中飞行
Again they had to convert these consumer cameras to NASA requirements.
同样 他们必须把这些消费者相机按照NASA的要求进行改装
The base cameras had the exterior level removed and they were simply painted matte black.
首先是去掉了原型相机的外壳 并被简单地涂成了亚光黑色
NASA stipulated that they had to have special vacuum safe lubricants.
NASA规定 他们必须使用特殊的可用于真空的润滑剂
They had different soldering standards.
同时 相机的焊接标准也进行了修改
Many of the plastic parts were replaced by metal.
许多塑料部件都被金属替代了
And the film transport mechanism had to handle the thinner polyester film used by NASA
同时需要确保胶片传输机构能够使用NASA较薄的聚酯纤维胶片
and that meant of course that they could fit many more photos onto a roll of film.
(NASA之所以使用较薄的胶片) 当然是为了在同样的胶卷中容纳更多的胶片
And of course there were many exterior modifications to make the cameras easier to use.
当然也有许多外观上的修改 使相机更易使用
You know larger controls, removal of strap lugs.
会有更大的控制机构 同时去掉用于吊带的挂环
Because having a camera on a strap around your neck doesn't make sense in 0g.
因为在失重的情况下 没法把相机通过带子挂在脖子上
And modifications of the viewfinder to make it work through a spacesuit.
还有对取景器的修改 这样即使穿着宇航服也能使用
Now I don't have time to go into any of the detail on this
那么我没时间去细说这些了
but Timm Chapman is a camera collector who owns several NASA Nikons
但蒂姆-查普曼是一个相机收藏家 他拥有几台NASA的尼康相机
and he's done a lot of research writing some white papers on the modifications
他做了很多研究 写了一些关于这些改装细节的报告
as well as compiling the serial numbers of the NASA hardware.
以及编写NASA设备的序列号
If you want to know any more detail on the NASA Nikons his site is the place to go.
如果你想知道NASA尼康相机的任何更多细节 可以去访问他的网站
So yeah the first NASA approved Nikon flown was a modified Nikon F SLR
那么第一个NASA批准上天的尼康相机是一个改装过的尼康F单反
and it was flown on Apollo 15.
这在阿波罗15号上得到使用
It was part of an experiment to observe space dust.
它是观察空间尘埃实验的一部分
When the command module was in the shadow of the moon
当指令舱处在月球的阴影中时
they would be pointed out the window and take a number of photos.
将相机指向窗外 拍下不少照片
Unfortunately there was an error in the coordinate systems
不幸的是 坐标系统出现了错误
and they ended up pointing the camera at the wrong part of the sky.
结果他们把相机进行了错误的指向 拍摄了天空中的其他区域
For Skylab they continued to use the same Nikon F but they added a motorized drive to it.
在天空实验室 他们继续使用同样的尼康F 但增加了一个电动驱动装置
It was used to photograph Earth through windows.
这台相机被用来通过窗户拍摄地球
It was used with filters to study earth's atmosphere
并搭配滤镜来研究地球的大气
and to check that the corona. This solar telescope was working.
同时还能查看日冕 作为一台太阳望远镜
By the time the Space Shuttle program came around
到了航天飞机计划的时候
they'd moved on to the Nikon F3.
他们已经换代到尼康F3上了
And depending upon mission requirements they had a small version and a large version.
根据任务要求 会使用一个较小版本或一个较大版本
The large version handled 250 exposures which was quite massive.
较大的版本可以进行250次曝光 这个能力相当不错
The F3 would also be used on EVAs.
F3也将被用于EVA
So it went outside. It would be covered by thermal blankets to stabilize the temperature.
那么这台相机会暴露在外太空 这样它会被隔热毯覆盖以稳定温度
MMU=Manned Maneuvering Unit，机动载人装置，曾在1984年的3个航天飞机任务中使用过3次后退役
and you can actually see one attached to Bruce McCandless MMU when he's free flying in space.
当布鲁斯·麦坎德勒斯在太空中自由飞行时 实际上你可以看到一台这样的相机连接到他的MMU
Of course the camera that took this image was a 70 millimeter Hasselblad.
当然 拍摄这张照片的相机是70毫米的哈苏
So the next big step forward would be in 1991
那么下一个大的进步是在1991年
with the flight of the Nikon F4 ESC, Electronic Still Camera.
随着尼康F4无反相机的升空
This began the transition to digital photography.
由此开始了向数码摄影的过渡
This camera was built out of a regular F4 SLR body
这款相机是在普通的F4单反机身的基础上制造出来的
but with a 1024, 1024 8-bit monochrome image sensor in the focal plane.
但在焦平面上有一个1024 x 1024(约105万像素)的8位的单色图像传感器
The sensor had actually originally been developed for use on the Hubble Space Telescope.
这个传感器最初实际上是为哈勃太空望远镜开发的
So the camera was bulky.
那么这台相机很笨重
It stored images to a hard disk.
它将图像存储在硬盘上
But it was hugely advantageous to be able to transmit the images to the ground
但能够将图像传输到地面是非常有利的
where they would get processed by a pixar image computer and print it out.
这样 图像就会被(地面的)皮克斯图像电脑进行处理 并打印出来
And this was especially useful.
而这会特别有用
Say if you're on a mission, you've grabbed a satellite from space
比如说如果你在执行任务 你从太空中抓到了一颗卫星
and you need help from the ground to solve problems.
而你需要地面的帮助来解决问题
You know, a picture literally is a thousand words.
很明显 一张图片所蕴含的信息量真的很大
There was a second digital camera floating around the same time.
同一时间 还有第二款数码相机在太空中使用
It was developed by Kodak and known as the Hawkeye II
它是由柯达公司开发的 被称为鹰眼二代
and while it only flew in a single test flight
虽然它只进行了一次测试使用
it did actually end up being the basis for Kodak's DCS 100
但它实际上最终成为了柯达DCS 100的基础
which is arguably the first commercial digital SLR.
可以说是第一台商用数码单反相机
Both cameras were actually being tested for an interesting payload called Hercules
这两款相机实际上都是在测试一个有趣的有效载荷 叫大力神
which would use inertial measurement units attached to the camera to measure the orientation.
它将使用附着在相机上的惯性测量单位(IMU)来测量方位
So it could tag images with their longitude and latitude on the ground.
因此 它可以在地面上用经度和纬度标记图像
The system would take the orbit of the Space Shuttle
该系统将以航天飞机的轨道为基准
and then the astronaut would align the camera with some reference stars
然后宇航员会将相机与一些参考星对准
and then after that the system could figure out where the camera was being pointed thanks to the IMU.
而后 系统可以计算出相机的指向 这就得归功于IMU了
Now my phone has an IMU in it and it's the size of a tiny microchip
现在我的手机里就有一个IMU 它的大小类似于一个小小的微芯片
but back then the IMUs were huge physical gyroscopes that
但当时的IMU是巨大的物理陀螺仪
and if you look in the photo it's that big cylinder attached to the bottom of the camera there.
如果你看照片 就是那个连接到相机底部的大圆筒
So the first commercial digital camera used in space was apparently the DCS 460
那么第一台在太空中使用的商用数码相机显然是DCS 460
which was again a Nikon body with a digital back
这又是一个带数码后背的尼康机身
and I think the whole thing cost something like twenty eight thousand dollars
我想这整个机器的成本大概是两万八千美元左右
but for that you got six megapixels of color imagery at 12 bits per pixel
但你得到了600万像素 每像素12位色深的彩色图像
and the ability to take an image every 12 seconds.
以及每12秒拍摄一张图像的能力
They could fit 42 images on the 260 megabyte hard drives that would fit into their PC slot.
这可以在260兆字节(MB)的硬盘上装下42张图像 而硬盘可以装进电脑插槽
Over time of course they'd upgrade. They had the DCS 660, the 760.
随着时间的推移 当然会进行升级 比如DCS 660和DCS 760
They got better and cheaper thanks to moore's law.
由于摩尔定律 它们变得更好更便宜
And it's also worth noting that
而且值得注意的是
these digital cameras were actually still based on the Nikon F-series bodies.
这些数码相机实际上还是基于尼康F系列机身的
So astronauts who used one would be sort of familiar with the other.
所以宇航员用过其中的一台就会对另一台比较熟悉
In fact sometimes you'll see astronauts refer to the DCS 760 as the digital F5
事实上 有时你会看到宇航员把DCS 760称为数码版F5
which brings me to the last film camera used by NASA in space.
这让我想到了NASA在太空中使用的最后一台胶片相机
The Nikon F5 and it made its debut on Endeavour in 1998.
也就是尼康F5 其在1998年首次在奋进号上使用
By this point Nikon had incorporated most of NASA's requirements into their regular production
此时尼康已经将NASA的大部分要求纳入了他们的常规产品当中
so the cameras were almost identical to those in stores.
所以相机和商店里卖的几乎是一样的
These were carried on EVAs and were something of a step up from the F3
这些相机是在EVA上携带的 是F3的升级版
since they added auto focus capability.
因为他们增加了自动对焦功能
There's a lot of out out-of-focus shots from you know spacewalks.
(这是因为)在太空行走中拍摄的照片很多都失焦了
Nowadays of course everything is digital.
现在当然一切都数字化了
According to wikipedia
根据维基百科
there's at least 10 types of Nikon digital SLR that have been used on the space station.
至少有10种尼康数码单反在空间站上使用过
The current NASA standard I believe is the Nikon D5.
目前NASA的标准我相信是尼康D5
But you know the advantages of instant feedback are one thing
但即时反馈的优势只是数码相机的一个特点 (不是说没有这个优势你就不能用胶片了)
but even if you want to use film
但即使你想用胶片
there's this problem that missions to the space station last month.
有这样一个问题 那就是空间站的任务一般都持续数月
And because of the higher radiation in low earth orbit
由于近地轨道的辐射较高
the film fogs up from radiation exposure.
胶片会因为辐射的曝光而模糊
And that's a problem that never mattered as much on the Space Shuttle
而这个问题在航天飞机并没有这么严重
because it only stayed in orbit for a couple of weeks.
因为它只在轨道上呆几个星期
Skylab actually had a radiation hardened film vault
而天空实验室实际上有一个防辐射的胶片储藏室
and that's so that they could protect it.
而这样就可以保护胶片不被辐射曝光
And when Skylab broke up and re-entry
而在天空实验室解体再入的时候
some of the biggest chunks of debris that made it to the surface were the vaults.
残骸中最大的一些块状物抵达了地面 其中就包括这个胶片储藏室的部分
On the other hand, cameras on the ISS can get permanent bad pixels from radiation damage
另一方面 国际空间站上的相机会因辐射损伤而产生永久的坏像素
so it's not all good news for being digital in space.
所以在太空中使用数字技术也不是尽善尽美的
But I don't see that as a technical argument for returning to film.
但我不认为这是回归胶片的技术论据
Ultimately as the cost of space travel drops
最终随着太空旅行成本的下降
and we start to see some space tours.
我们会看到一些太空旅游开始进行
Maybe we'll see some of them deciding to return to film again for artistic reasons.
也许其中一些太空游客 会因为艺术的原因而重新使用胶片摄影
I'm Scott Manley. Fly safe.
我是Scott Manley 切记 注意飞行安全
[Music]
[音乐]